ratemyplacement.co.uk 2019-05-09

# Privacy Policy | RateMyPlacement Blog

## **What is a privacy policy and why is it important for you?**

A privacy policy is a statement that shows some or all of the ways we, RateMyPlacement.co.uk, use, disclose, and manage your data. We have a legal requirement to protect your privacy and that’s exactly what we intend to do.

We know that you care about how your information is used and shared and we appreciate your trust in us to do that carefully and sensibly.

At RateMyPlacement we use your data to help you find the best work experience opportunities for you. That is why we collect your data so we can:

  * **Send you emails**
    * So you can get personalised advice and information about particular job roles and industries that you are interested in
  * **Provide you with a personalised experience**
    * Shortlisting and favoriting companies means that you can then hear from them directly about new roles and what it’s like to work at the company.
    * We use cookies to help us to personalise your experience and interactions with us. This means we can see your behaviours on the website and then advertise the best opportunities for you as well as improve your user experience with us.
    * If you have looked at a particular employer on our website, we then use this information to advertise to you on your social media platforms and other websites so that you can keep that particular employer in mind.
  * **IP Addresses**
    * We capture the IP address of visitors to our websites. We use this data to analyse traffic patterns and block malicious bots and users.

Below is our privacy policy on how we use and manage your data and also forms part of our website terms and conditions.

We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of your personal data and are bound to comply with the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) laws and Data Protection Act 1998.

Your privacy is important to us. It is RateMyPlacement’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect from you across our website, https://www.ratemyplacement.co.uk and other sites we own and operate.

## **Your rights and responsibilities**

As a user of our website, you have the right to know about how your data is collected and used. You are allowed to know:

– What data we collect about you

– How it is processed

– That you can correct and update any personal information about you. You can amend or remove your account information at any time, using the tools provided in your [account control panel.](https://www.ratemyplacement.co.uk/dashboard/password)

You can restrict or object to how we use your data, while keeping your account with us for your own purposes. You have the right to opt out of your data being used in decisions through automated processes such as unsubscribing from emails or selecting your preferences on your account control panel.

## **Information we collect**

### **Personal information**

We may ask for personal information, such as your: 

  * First Name
  * Last Name
  * Email address
  * Gender
  * University
  * Degree area
  * Uni Start year
  * Uni Graduation Year
  * Type of opportunity you’re looking for (insight, internship, placement year)
  * Length of work experience
  * Roles of interest
  * Industries interested in
  * Location you’re interested in working in
  * Jobs, reviews and companies that you have actively shortlisted when logged in

We call this data “identifying information”, as it identifies who you are. We only ask for the above information so we can help you find the best and most relevant opportunities for you; as well as providing you with the best advice for your job hunt.

## **How we collect your information**

We only collect information by fair and lawful means, with your knowledge and consent. We also let you know why we’re collecting it and how it will be used. You are free to not give us this information however this could mean that we may be unable to provide you with some of RateMyPlacement’s services and features on the website.

## **How is your data collected**

  * When you sign up through the RateMyPlacement.co.uk login page
  * Through several touch points on the website including redundant pages, leaving the website to visit third party page, through shortlisting and favouriting job roles and companies.
  * Careers and freshers fairs we use forms to collect your data to set up an account
  * Through sign up forms on dedicated landing pages, accessed via Google Adwords and Facebook Advertising sources

### **Shortlisting feature**

  * Throughout the RateMyPlacement site we offer users the opportunity to: 
    * Follow Companies, denoted by a thumb icon.
    * Shortlist Jobs, denoted by a heart icon.
    * Favourite Reviews, denoted by a star icon.
  * When a user first performs one of these actions for a company we ask for consent to share their data with the employer they shortlist, follow or favourite. For example, a user shortlists a job for Company A, they are then shown a question asking whether they would like to share their data directly with Company A.
  * If a user makes no choice when asked this question, their data will not be shared.
  * If a user declines to opt in, that preference will be saved and they will not be asked again for that company. Their data will not be shared. This preference can be changed at a later date.
  * If a user opts in to share their data with employers, the following information will be passed to all the employer that the user shortlists, follows or favourites. 
    * First name
    * Surname
    * Email Address
    * Course
    * University
    * Graduation Year
    * Gender
    * The action they performed. e.g. shortlisting a job
  * If at a later date a user would like to stop sharing their data with employers, they can change their opt in preference in the my account section of RateMyPlacement.
  * Once the information has been passed to a third party employer, the users relation with regards to the data shared is with the third party employer.
  * If the user would like to remove or amend the shared data they should contact the third party employer directly.

### **From other sources:**

When you visit our website, our servers may automatically log the standard data provided by your web browser. It may include your computer’s Internet Protocol (IP) address, your browser type and version, the pages you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on each page, and other details. This data is retained for 7 days and is used for analysis of traffic patterns and blocking malicious bots and users.

## **Use of information**

We may use a combination of ‘identifying’ and ‘non-identifying’ information to understand who you are, how you use our website and your account, and how we may improve your experience of our website in future.

We do not share this information in detail publicly, however we may share aggregated and anonymised versions of this information, for example, in website and customer usage trend reports.

We may use your personal details to contact you about updates about our website and services, along with promotional content that you have given us permission to send to you.

If you wish to opt out of receiving promotional content, you can follow the “unsubscribe” instructions provided alongside any correspondence from us.

### **Data processing and storage**

The personal information we collect about you and our users is stored and processed in United Kingdom.

We only keep personal information for as long as necessary to provide a service, or to improve our services in future.

While we keep this data, we will protect it within commercially acceptable means to prevent loss and theft, as well as unauthorised access, disclosure, copying, use or modification. That said, we advise that no method of electronic transmission or storage is 100% secure, and cannot guarantee absolute data security.

We have appropriate security measures in place to prevent personal information from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way. We limit access to your personal information to those who have a genuine business need to know it. Those processing your information will do so only in an authorised manner and are subject to a duty of confidentiality. We also have procedures in place to deal with any suspected data security breach. We will notify you and any applicable regulator of a suspected data security breach where we are legally required to do so.

### **How is your data kept secure?**

We work to protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input.

We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards in connection with the collection, storage and disclosure of personally identifiable customer information. Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we disclose personal information to you.

It is important for you to protect against unauthorised access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when you finish using a shared computer.

### **How do you access and delete your data?**

To delete your account please visit <https://www.ratemyplacement.co.uk/dashboard/password> and click the ‘close account’ button shown in red.

## **Cookies**

We use “cookies” to collect information about you and your activity across our site.

### **What is a cookie?**

A cookie is a small piece of data that our website stores on your computer, and accesses each time you visit, so we can understand how you use our website. This helps us provide you content based on your previous activity and on preferences you have specified.

Cookies are used to enable certain features (eg. logging in), to track how you interact and use the website (eg. google analytics), to store your settings such as timezone, notification preferences and updates to your account, and to personalise your content to make sure it’s information you want / need.

Cookies set by the RateMyPlacement website are normally referred to as “first-party cookies”, and typically only track your activity on our website. Cookies set by other websites and companies (ie. employers websites which you visit when you click apply) are called “third-party cookies”, and can be used to track you on other websites that use the same third-party service.

Please refer to our Cookie Policy below for more information.

## **Third-party access to information**

We use third-party services for:

**Analytics tracking, advertising** and **promotion, email marketing**

These services only use our data for performing specific tasks on our behalf e.g. emailing you or letting us know if you left our website to apply for a role. We do not give them permission to disclose or use your our data for any other purpose.

### **Email Marketing**

We use a third party provider, Dotmailer, to deliver our emails. We gather statistics around email opens and clicks using industry standard technologies including clear gifs to help us monitor and improve our email communications.

### **Analytics Tracking**

When someone visits www.ratemyplacement.co.uk we use a third party service, Google Analytics, to collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns. We do this to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the site. This information is only processed in a way which does not identify anyone. We do not make, and do not allow Google to make, any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website. If we do want to collect personally identifiable information through our website, we will be up front about this. We will make it clear when we collect personal information and will explain what we intend to do with it.

We also make use of a third party service called Hotjar for recording heatmaps of where users click and scroll to on our site. Hotjar also allows us to ask visitors to answer polls and surveys when visiting our site. Hotjar will place cookies on your browser to ensure you aren’t show the same poll/survey multiple times if you have already completed or dismissed it. We do not expose any personally identifiable information to Hotjar.

### **Website Optimisation**

We make use of a third party tool called convert.com to optimise our website by A/B testing content and user journeys on our website. Convert.com will place cookies on to your browser to ensure you see the same version of an A/B test throughout the site. We do not expose any personally identifiable information to Convert.com.

## **Advertising and Promotion**

### **Google Adwords**

We make use of a third party service called Google Adwords to advertise our job listings and email alerts via adverts on Google Search results. We also use this tool for display marketing, which falls into either prospecting adverts (for those who have never been on our website) or retargeting adverts (for those who have been on RateMyPlacement.co.uk before). Google Adwords will place cookies on to your browser to identify what category you fall into, as well as to track if you have clicked one of our adverts. Any targeting is based solely on third party data acquired by Google, and is only open to us as aggregate data. We are not privy to your specific data. We also do not expose any of your own personally identifiable information to Google Adwords.

### **Facebook Tracking**

We make use of Facebook’s Advertising suite in order to create adverts of our services, which are hosted on a variety of areas within Facebook, including its news feed, Instagram’s photo feed and Facebook Messenger. Facebook will place cookies on to your browser to track if you view or click one of our ads. Any targeting is based solely on any information you have given to Facebook, and is only open to us as aggregate data. We are not privy to your specific data. We also do not expose any of your own personally identifiable information to Facebook.

### **Push Notifications**

We use a third party service called ‘OneSignal’ to send job vacancies via push notifications in browser – these push notifications are consent based. If you consent to receiving push notifications from RateMyPlacement none of your personal data is sent to OneSignal. When you consent to receiving push notifications you are assigned an anonymous unique identifier for the particular device that you are using; these unique identifiers are used to track your subscription to push notifications as well as us being able to track analytical data of the individual push notifications such as the number of clicks a push notification has received.

If you wish to opt-out of push notifications from RateMyPlacement you can do so following instructions found [here](https://pushassist.com/blog/how-to-disable-push-notifications-on-chrome-firefox-safari-browser/).

This policy is effective as of 25 May 2018.

## **Cookie Policy**

We use cookies to help improve your experience of [https://www.ratemyplacement.co.uk](https://www.ratemyplacement.co.uk/), and covers the use of cookies between your device and our website.

We also provide basic information on third-party services we use, who may also use cookies as part of their service, please note these are not covered by our policy.

If you don’t wish to accept cookies from us, you can amend the settings on your browser to refuse cookies from [https://www.ratemyplacement.co.uk](https://www.ratemyplacement.co.uk/). If you do this then we may be unable to provide you with some of your preferred information, content and services.

## **Types of cookies and how we use them**

### **Essential cookies**

Essential cookies are crucial to your experience of a website, enabling core features like user logins, account management, shopping carts and payment processing. We use essential cookies to enable certain functions on our website.

### **Cookies we use:**

**Cookie Description** | **Function & Content** | **Permission**  
---|---|---  
Logged In (Session) | Present if a registered RateMyPlacement.co.uk user is logged in. | Registered user explicitly requests permission to login and view their content. Required for usual website use as a registered user.  
Job Application Screening Passed | When a user applies for a job via the website, we set a cookie to enable you to proceed once you pass the initial screening questions. Functionally required in order to process your application in line with the requirements of our companies. Usage not tracked. | We do not ask additional permission because we classify this as essential behaviour to the task of validating the job application you are constructing.  
Job Suggestion Box | When you visit our site if you look at a number of jobs, but are not logged in as a registered user, we suggest you may wish to sign up for our newsletters. The message appears once then disappears. Usage is not tracked. | We do not track the usage of this cookie.  
Google Analytics | We use Google Analytics to monitor our site traffic, and we do this anonymously. | You passively set this cookie when you visit any of our websites.  
Convert.com | We use Convert.com to perform a/b split tests on our site, and we do this anonymously. | You passively set this cookie when you visit any of our websites.  
HotJar | We use Hotjar to monitor our site traffic, run polls and questionnaires, as well as screen recording to monitor how users use our site, we do this anonymously. | You passively set this cookie when you visit any of our websites.  
OneSignal | We use OneSignal to present opt in notifications for push notifications, and we do this anonymously. | You passively set this cookie when you visit any of our websites.  
Google Adwords | We use Adwords conversion tracking to monitor users behaviour on our website for both static and dynamic retargeting. | You passively set this cookie when you visit any of our websites.  
Facebook & Instagram | We use Facebook pixel to monitor our site traffic, and then serve messages that may interest you on Facebook and Instagram based on what you have viewed on our site. | You passively set this cookie when you visit any of our websites.  
  
### **How you can control or opt out of cookies**

If you don’t want to accept cookies from us, you can change the settings on your browser to refuse cookies from RateMyPlacement. Most internet browsers have default settings to accept cookies by default, but you can update these settings at any time to either refuse cookies altogether, or to notify you when a website is trying to set or update a cookie.

If you browse websites from multiple devices e.g. phone and tablet, you may need to update your settings on each individual device.

Although some cookies can be blocked without noticing the impact on your experience of a website, blocking all cookies can result in being unable to access certain features and content across the sites you visit.

## **Children’s Privacy**

This website does not knowingly target children, or collect personal information from children. As a parent/guardian, please contact us if you believe your child is participating in an activity involving personal information on our website, and you have not received a notification or request for consent. We do not use your supplied contact details for marketing or promotional purposes.

## **Limits of our policy**

This privacy policy only covers RMP Enterprise Ltd.’s own collecting and handling of data.

Our website may link to external sites that are not operated by us. Please be aware that we have no control over the content and policies of those sites, and cannot accept responsibility or liability for their respective privacy practices.

## **Changes to this policy**

At our discretion, we may change our privacy policy to reflect current acceptable practices. We will take reasonable steps to let users know about changes via our website. If you have an account with https://www.ratemyplacement.co.uk, we will notify you using the contact details saved in your account. Your continued use of this site after any changes to this policy will be regarded as acceptance of our practices around privacy and personal information.

## **How to contact us**

If you want to request information about our privacy policy you can [email](https://www.ratemyplacement.co.uk/contact-us) us or write to:

RMP Enterprise Ltd.  
9 Brighton Terrace  
Brixton  
London  
SW9 8DJ

Feel free to contact us if you have any concerns or questions about how we handle your data and personal information.

RMP Enterprise Ltd. Data Controller

Overview of Privacy Policy

Last updated: May 2018

This policy applies to:

  * RateMyPlacement.co.uk, RMP Enterprise ltd. (registered number 6331665).
  * RMP Enterprise Ltd. **9 Brighton Terrace, Brixton, London, SW9 8DJ**
